Guide to the Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyana and British Methodism, 1536-1996 and undated RL.00413
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1632-1637, 1710, 1738-1966, 1988, and undated, 17 boxes, approx. 3000 items
  - Alphabetical File: Individual Letters Subseries, 1710-1922, and undated
    - Triggs, William to Mrs. Jenner; Cain's Cross, 1805 Feb. 12 (Box CO 11)
    - Tyerman, L[uke], to various correspondents, 1864-69, 1886, 4 items (Box CO 11)
    - Walther?, Sunderland, to Rev. Southern, [18]78 April 27 (Box CO 11, Folder W)
    - Watson, James, Northwich, to Richard Rodda, BroadMead, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 2 (Box CO 11)
      Re: sacrament controversy.
    - Wheeler, Robert, Newport, Isle of Wight, to B. Slater, Methodist Chapel, Margate, Kent, 1821 Aug. 18 (Box CO 11)
    - Willcox, Robert, Nottingham, to Mr. and Mrs. W[illia]m Sharpe, Portsmouth, 1840 March 10 (Box CO 11)
    - Wilson, Martha, n.p., to ?, n.p., 1738 June 19 and undated (Box CO 11)
    - Winter, [?], Painswick, to Mr. Lee, Wem, Shropshire, 1797 May 26 (Box CO 11)
    - Wood, Thomas, Bristol, to William Shrewsbury, Wesleyan Missionary, Grenada, 1818 Dec. 11 (Box CO 11)
    - Church Missionary Society: handwritten note announcing a sermon at Aycliffe, 1849 July 1 (Box CO 11, Folder Unidentified Correspondence)
    - Letter printed by Thomas Cordeux detailing a complaint and resolution made concerning membership in the Society "At a meeting of the Preachers and Leaders of Classes in the London East Circuit," New-Chapel, City-Road, 1811, Nov. 26 (Box CO 11)
      Handwritten draft of a letter concerning the whereabouts of books (some were Wesley's) from the accused thief? (I "would not presume to take it away until you came to town and gave me permission"). Undated, unaddressed, unsigned, and apparently unrelated to the printed material.
    - First leaf of letter (incomplete) about the beginning of Conference (election of George Morley as President, plans to address the new King William IV), unaddressed and unsigned, [1830 July - in pencil]. (Box CO 11)
    - 6 pages (three sheets - incomplete) addressing the pecuniary problems of the Methodist connexion. Lists reasons why their debt has increased and possible solutions. Unsigned, unaddressed, and undated. (Box CO 11)
  - Methodist Preachers Subseries, circa 1790-1940 and undated, 2 boxes, 750 items
    Letters received as a discrete alphabetical file in the Frank Baker Papers. Predominantly from mid-to-late 19th century English Methodist preachers, most often addressed to Samuel Simpson, and with subject matter often focusing on times, locations, and other details of various preaching assignments and invitations. A frequent topic is the Education Fund. F. F. Bretherton's name also appears frequently, and he was likely Baker's immediate source for some of these letters. Certain longer and older letters, circa 1775-1825, have been transferred to various subseries in the Correspondence Series, particularly to James Everett. Arranged alphabetically to folder level.
    - Correspondence, Folders A-L, circa 1790 -1940 and undated (Box CO 12)
    - Correspondence, Folders M-Y, circa 1790 -1940 and undated (Box CO 13)
  - Presidents' Letters Subseries, 1777-1966, 1988, and undated, 2 boxes, 750 items
    These materials, received as a discrete alphabetical file in the Frank Baker Papers, were transferred to the Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyana and British Methodism because of many of the Presidents' direct connections with many of the historical figures in the main body of the Correspondence Series. The file came with a brief checklist of Wesleyan Methodist Conference and Methodist Conference Presidents and other information about the history of this office. Arranged alphabetically by name.
    - Presidents' Letters Information, 1851-1907, 1954, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Allen, Thomas, 1900, 1903 (Box CO 14)
    - Armstrong, Walter H. 1941, 1909, 1946-1948 (Box CO 14)
    - Atherton, William, 1812-1813, 1834, 1845-1846, and undated
      - 1834 May 21, Atherton, Bath, ALS to Theophilus Lessey (Box CO 14)
      - 1843 Jan., ALS "Rev. John" [address torn off] (Box CO 14)
        Mounted in Volume WP II:81. Note to remind the Mission House to pay him (Atherton) the interest on 120 pounds owed him.
      - 1845 Nov. 19, Atherton, Manchester, ALS to John Shipman (Box CO 14)
    - Atmore, Charles, 1811, 1811, 1824, 1825 and undated
      - 1825 May 16, Cheapside, London, ALS to "The preachers in the Sheffield District" (Box CO 14)
        Mounted in Volume WP II:35. Four pages to let them know he cannot attend upcoming District meeting due to his health problems.
    - Banks, John Shaw, 1902, undated (Box CO 14)
    - Barber, John, 1807, 1815, 1811, 1957 (Box CO 14)
    - Barber, William, T.A. 1919, 1919 (Box CO 14)
    - Bedford, John, 1867, 1850, 1860-1868 (Box CO 14)
    - Beecham, John, 1844, 1850, 1854, 1856, undated (Box CO 14)
    - Benson, Joseph (Box CO 14)
    - Bett, Henry, 1940, 1945-1949 (Box CO 14)
    - Bond, Robert, 1937, 1938 (Box CO 14)
    - Bowers, John, 1858, 1834, 1851, 1859-1863 (Box CO 14)
    - Bradford, Joseph, 1795, 1803, 1780, 1787, 1791 (Box CO 14)
    - Burnet, Amos, 1924, undated (Box CO 14)
    - Bush, Joseph, 1888, 1841 (Box CO 14)
    - Chadwick, Joseph, 1918, undated (Box CO 14)
    - Church, Leslie F., 1943, 1949-1951 (Box CO 14)
    - Clarke, Adam--SEE CORRESPONDENCE SERIES (Box CO 14)
    - Clayton, Albert, 1906, 1906 (Box CO 14)
    - Davison, W.T., 1901, 1899-1904 (Box CO 14)
    - Dixon, James, 1841, 1825 (Box CO 14)
    - Entwisle, Joseph, 1812, 1825, 1802-1804, 1819-1831, 1848-1849 (Box CO 14)
    - Farndale, W.E., 1947, 1946-1959 (Box CO 14)
    - Farrar, Dorothy, 1959 (Box CO 14)
    - Farrar, John--Six manuscript items, circa 1829-1864 (Box CO 14)
      Four autograph letters and one fragment, signed, likely written by the younger John Farrar (1802-1884). One autograph manuscript, signed, likely written by the elder John Farrar (ministry commenced 1796, died 1837).
    - Flew, R. N., 1946, 1953-1954 (Box CO 14)
    - Garrett, Charles--correspondence and portraits, 1882-1893 and undated, 17 items (Box CO 14)
    - Gaulter, John--autograph and typed transcription, 1819 and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Green, Walford--autograph, undated (Box CO 14)
    - Greeves, Frederic--correspondence, 1866-1895 and undated, 3 items (Box CO 14)
    - Gregory, Benjamin--correspondence and autographs, 1854, 1885, 1897, and undated, 6 items (Box CO 14)
    - Griffith, Walter, 1808-1810 (Box CO 14)
    - Grindrod, Edmund, 1837, 1820-1839, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Haigh, Henry, 1911, 1897, 1915, 1917 (Box CO 14)
    - Hall, Samuel Romilly, 1868, 1892, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Handy, Thomas William, 1794, 1959 (Box CO 14)
    - Hannah, John, 1842, 1851, 1838-1865, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Harrison, A. W. 1945, 1925-1945 (Box CO 14)
    - Hartley, Marshall 1903, 1903, 1909, 1926 (Box CO 14)
    - Hornabrook, John, 1910, 1902-1924 (Box CO 14)
    - Howard, Wilbert F., 1944, 1944 (Box CO 14)
    - Hughes, Hugh Price, H. Maldwyn, 1883-1903, 1917-1923, 1959, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Humphrey, William, 1935 (Box CO 14)
    - Hulme, T. Ferrierr, 1923, 1933-1939 (Box CO 14)
    - Jackson, William, 1935, 1925-1940 (Box CO 14)
    - James, John H., 1871, 1857-1858, 1870, 1872, 1891, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Jenkins, Ebenezer, 1880, 1872-1897 (Box CO 14)
    - Jobson, Frederic J.--correspondence, autographs, typed transcription, and image, 1848-1878, 1961, and undated, 17 items (Box CO 14)
    - Johnson, Simpson, 1917, 1911 and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Keeling, Issac, 1855, 1850-1856 (Box CO 14)
    - Kelly, Charles, 1889, 1905, 1882-1906 (Box CO 14)
    - Lessy, Theophilus, 1823-1835, and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Lidgett, John Scott, 1908, 1932, 1907-1910 and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Lofthouse, W.F., 1949-1958 (Box CO 14)
    - Lomas, John, 1853, 1859 and undated (Box CO 14)
    - McCullagh, Thomas 1883, 1882-1903 (Box CO 14)
    - Marsden, George, 1815-1844 and undated (Box CO 14)
    - Mather, Alexander--SEE CORRESPONDENCE SERIES (Box CO 14)
    - Morley, George, 1830, 1804, 1829, 1838 (Box CO 14)
    - Moss, R. Waddy, 1915, 1903 (Box CO 14)
    - Moulton, W.F., 1890, 1890, 1892, 1901 (Box CO 14)
    - Murray, Victor, 1958 (Box CO 14)
    - Newton, Dr. Robert--SEE CORRESPONDENCE SERIES (Box CO 14)
    - Noble, Walter J., 1942, 1946 (Box CO 15)
    - Osborn, George--SEE CORRESPONDENCE SERIES (Box CO 15)
    - Pawson, John, 1793, 1801, 1796-1805, 1900-1901, 1916 (Box CO 15)
    - Perkins, Benson, 1948, 1939-1952 (Box CO 15)
    - Perkins, William, 1909, 1888, 1898, 1908 (Box CO 15)
    - Perks, George T., 1873, 1864, 1893, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Pope, Henry J., 1893, 1894 (Box CO 15)
    - Pope, Rev. William, 1877-1883, 1903 and 1988 (Box CO 15)
    - Prest, Charles, 1862, 1846-1874 and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Punshon, William Morley, 1849-1911 (Box CO 15)
    - Pyke, Richard, 1939, 1939, 1945 (Box CO 15)
    - Randles, Marshall, 1896, 1894, 1896, 1897 (Box CO 15)
    - Rattenbury, John, 1841-1876, 1950, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Reece, Richard, 1816, 1835, 1817, 1838-1841 (Box CO 15)
      Includes autograph letter to James Everett, 1817 July 24, informing Everett of his appointment to York.
    - Rigg, James H., 1878, 1892, 1876-1903 (Box CO 15)
    - Ritson, John H., 1925, 1926-1949 (Box CO 15)
    - Roberts, Colins, 1952, 1948 (Box CO 15)
    - Roberts, Harold, 1957, 1946-1948 (Box CO 15)
    - Roberts, Richard, 1885, 1860-1896 (Box CO 15)
    - Sangster, William, 1950, 1946-1960 (Box CO 15)
    - Scott, John, 1829-1862 and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Sharf, J. Alfred, 1921, 1910-1913, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Shaw, William, 1865, 1856, 1862-1865 (Box CO 15)
    - Shearer, William Russell, 1954, 1939, 1946 (Box CO 15)
    - Simon, John S., 1907, 1764, 1922 (Box CO 15)
    - Smith, C. Ryder, 1947-1956 (Box CO 15)
    - Smith, Gervase, undated (Box CO 15)
    - Snaith, Norman, undated (Box CO 15)
    - Soper, Donald O. 1953, 1939-1959, 1966 (Box CO 15)
    - Stanley, Jacob, 1845, 1809, 1833-1845 (Box CO 15)
    - Stephenson, Thomas Bowman, 1891, 1874 and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Tasker, J.G., 1916, 1889, 1935 (Box CO 15)
    - Taylor, Joseph, 1834, 1841, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Taylor, Thomas, 1780, 1799 (Box CO 15)
    - Thompson, William, 1777, 1782, 1791-1792, 1801, 1959, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Thornton, William L., 1791, 1842, 1851, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Treffry, Richard, 1833, 1818-1842, 1945 (Box CO 15)
    - Tudor, Leonard, 1952 (Box CO 15)
    - Waddy, Samuel, D., 1859, 1866-1871 (Box CO 15)
    - Waller, D.J., 1895, 1891, 1892, 1895 (Box CO 15)
    - Walters, C. Esnor, 1936, undated (Box CO 15)
    - Walters, H. Crawford, 1956, undated (Box CO 15)
    - Walton, John, 1887, 1864-1871, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Wardle, W. Lansdell, 1938, 1941-1944 (Box CO 15)
    - Watkins-Jones, Howard, 1951, 1951 (Box CO 15)
    - Watkinson, William, L. 1897, 1885-1907, 1923 and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Watson, Richard, 1826, 1814-1831 (Box CO 15)
    - Weatherhead, Leslie, 1955, 1941, 1959, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Whitehead, Silvester, 1904, 1890-1911 (Box CO 15)
    - Wiseman, F. Luke, 1912, 1933, 1912-1933 (Box CO 15)
    - Wiseman, Luke H., 1872, 1872, 1873, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Wood, James
      - Correspondence, 1798, 1800, 1822, 1956 (Box CO 15)
      - Wood, James, Manchester, to [?], n.p., 1834 Mar. 6 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
        Manuscript letter on verso of circular letter, At a Meeting of Gentlemen, Members of the Wesleyan-Methodist Society, held in Manchester, on the 26th February, 1834.
    - Workman, H.B., 1930, 1943-1948 (Box CO 15)
    - Young, Dinsdale T., 1914, 1911-1926 (Box CO 15)
    - Young, Robert Newton, 1886, 1854, 1874, 1892, and undated (Box CO 15)
    - Younger, William, 1934, 1939 (Box CO 15)
    - Unidentified, 1852-1920 and undated (Box CO 15)
  - Collectors' Correspondence Subseries, 1833-1953 and undated, 400 items
    Small collection of correspondence without provenance, discovered loose amongst Baker's papers. The bulk appears to be correspondence Baker inherited (by gift or purchase) from earlier collectors of Wesleyana and Methodist manuscripts active in the late 19th to early 20th centuries, especially John Austen and G. B. Cocking. In addition to correspondence directly to or from Austen and Cocking, there are numerous letters from late 19th century Methodist preachers and Wesleyan presidents, so that there is some overlap in content with the two subseries immediately preceding this one. Arranged chronologically, by decade, with the exception of the folder of Presidents' Letters described below.
    - Collectors' correspondence, 1850-1953 and undated, 11 folders (Box CO 16)
    - Presidents' Letters, 1833-1932 (Box CO 16)
      Contains a number of letters from Wesleyan presidents and ministers. A detailed list of letters at the beginning of the folder appears to be for research purposes only, not a list of contents; however, the list may overlap with items to be found elsewhere in this collection.
- Methodist Class and Band Tickets Series, 1742-1958 and undated, 4 boxes, 11 volumes
  Consists mainly of albums of Methodist class and band tickets; also contains many loose tickets and groups of Methodist class papers and books; and research material on these and related topics. The "class meeting" and "class ticket" refer back to the earliest years of Wesley's Methodist societies, with the class paper introduced to record attendance at the meetings and the class tickets distributed to members quarterly. The series contains more than 4000 tickets, most of them mounted in albums or scrapbooks. The volumes vary greatly in size and physical condition, from booklets scarcely larger than the tickets themselves (about 2" x 3"), to large scrapbooks with many items coming loose, to such beautifully-preserved albums as the Joseph G. Wright Class and Band Tickets, 1742-1954.
  Though mainly from English churches, there are also multiple examples from other countries, including tickets printed in Welsh, German, and Tamil. In addition to the Wesleyan Methodist church, several other denominations are represented, including the Primitive Methodist Church, the Wesleyan Reform Church, the Wesleyan Reform Union, and the modern unified Methodist Church.
  The class papers and books are the records kept by class leaders, who recorded not only attendance but also commented upon the spiritual status and progress of individual members. Also contained in this series are various articles and notes by Baker and other scholars on the class meetings and tickets; this secondary material explains not only the history of such materials but also their possible uses for historical research, including local history, genealogy, administration of the growing church was administrated at the local level. Finally, although by the 19th century the tickets had become entirely textual items, many of the earliest tickets were visually elaborate and contain hundreds of examples of 18th century engraving technique.
  - Correspondence, Notes, Research, and Printed Materials, 1953-1970 and undated (Box MCB 1)
  - On Class Meetings, Manuscript transcription, 1790 (Box MCB 1)
  - Class Attendance, Loose Tickets (1788-1957), and The Evolution of the Class Ticket, draft (Box MCB 1)
  - A Methodist Class Paper, 1804, 1826, and undated (Box MCB 1)
    Contains: Methodist class paper, 1804; Methodist class ticket, 1826; and undated explanatory text by FB, probably for an exhibit or class.
  - Miscellaneous memoranda relating to class tickets: clippings, correspondence, notes, tickets, and 1842 class book, 1816-1959 and undated (Box MCB 1)
  - Class books, 1952-1954 and undated, 2 envelopes (Box MCB 1)
  - Tickets
    - Loose tickets (in envelopes), 1797-1909 and undated, 2 envelopes (Box MCB 1)
    - Loose tickets, 1823-1953 (Box MCB 1)
    - Tickets from post, 3 envelopes, 1827-1836 and 1900s (Box MCB 1)
    - Preston, 1800s, 8 folders (Box MCB 2)
      Class tickets of various members of the Jackson family of Preston.
    - Ticket envelopes, undated, 2 items (Box MCB 2)
  - Ticket albums and scrapbooks, 1754-1954
    - Baldwin, A. H., Scrapbook, Methodist Class Tickets: 100 Years, A.H. Baldwin, 1811-1914, 250 tickets (Box MCB 2)
    - Baldwin George, Scrapbook of mounted and loose class tickets and correspondence, 1754-1944, 1200 tickets (Box MCB 2)
    - Two bound booklets (Box MCB 3)
      - Mellow, Bessie, and Mr. Wills, Scrapbook of class tickets, 1839-1895, 20 tickets (Box MCB 3)
      - Stones, Joseph, Class book, 1852-1856 (Box MCB 3)
    - Nunn, William and Mary, Two bound booklets of Wesleyan-Methodist Society class tickets, 1835-1863, 100 tickets (Box MCB 3)
    - Rowe, Mr. and Mrs. Thos. S., of Margate, Scrapbook of class tickets, 1807-1864, 300 tickets (Box MCB 3)
    - Shaw, William Turner, Album of class tickets, 1838-1859, 70 tickets (Box MCB 3)
    - John Wesley Class Tickets Album, 1932-1949, 74 tickets (Box MCB 3)
    - Wright, J. G., Scrapbook of tickets, incomplete, 1807-1903, 300 tickets (Box MCB 3)
      Content: many tickets are loose within the volume, and others seem to missing entirely.
    - Joseph G. Wright Class and Band Tickets, 1742-1954, 977 tickets (Box MCB 4)
      Compiled by Joseph G. Wright (d. 1911) of Wolverhampton, England, and completed to 1932 by F. F. Bretherton. Gift of FB, 1982, at which time he deemed it one of the two or three largest collections in the world.
  - Photographs Subseries, 1567-1934 and undated, 3 boxes
    Small subseries houses photographic materials collected by Frank Baker, including albumen and modern prints of places and people, panoramic photographs of Methodist groups and meetings, and glass plate negatives of archival materials housed in Cliff College, Derbyshire. Earliest subseries date reflects image content contained in a glass plate negative.
    - Albumen: mounted image of storefront of Turner & Drinkwater Artists and Photographers, with small child standing to the side, after 1878 (Box VM 33)
      Studio was established in Hull, England in 1878.
    - F. F. Bretherton photograph album, 1896-1933 and undated, 2 folders, 5 unbound pages, 37 items (Box VM 33)
      Photograph album, received disbound, probably compiled by F. F. Bretherton and given to Frank Baker, and was part of Frank Baker's papers. Bretherton, according to a news clipping,was the Secretary of the Wesley Historical Society. Contains 41 pasted-in photographs: group portraits of house parties, estate grounds, country houses, and small head-shots of individuals, chiefly women. Place-names include Holkham Hall, Poulton, Norfolk; Leckhampton Court, North Cheltenham; Elton Hall, Peterborough; Shane's Castle, Antrim; Howth Castle, County Dublin; Castle Boro, Enniscorthy; Powerscourt, Enniskerry; and Patshull House, Wolverhampton. Typically each page is dedicated to an estate and a house party, with a list of participants and an array of related photos; one includes a pasted-in tally of a shooting party. Also contains some letters, news clippings on Methodist and Wesley family history, clippings on weddings and deaths, and other manuscript items, received in the same binder.
    - Churches (Methodist)--primarily exterior views, including but not limited to Devonport, Kent, and Poundsbridge, 1894, 1934, and undated, 19 items (Box VM 33)
    - European and South American locales, including Naples, Rome, Genova, Buenos Aires, and Jersey, 1910 and undated, 11 items (Box VM 34)
    - Methodist preachers--individual and group portraits, including several with family members, 1909, 1913, and undated, 2 folders, 23 items (Box VM 34)
    - Images of Methodist-related documents from Cliff College library collections, glass plate negatives, 1527-1920s and undated, 26 items (Box VM 35)
      Negative glass plate images of engravings, title pages, portraits, or texts, from the archival collections at Cliff College, Derbyshire, England, photographer unknown. Dates reflect image content and not the date of the photograph was taken. About half of the plates are accompanied by a positive print. Authors or subjects include Jane Catherine March (photograph of a letter); Sam Wesley (excerpts from the Coryat); Sally Wesley (letter); John Bennett; Josiah Dornford (letter); Hogarth (engraving, "Credulity, Superstition, Fanaticism: a Medley"); and a portrait of Charles Wesley.
    - Wesley at his mother's tomb: Kodak "Lightning Plate," undated (Box VM 35)
      RELATED MATERIAL: This may be an image of either the engraving The Visit of the Rev. John Wesley, A.M., to His Mother's Grave, A.D. 1779 (Bunhill Fields), housed in Wesley Family Series, Wesley Family Portraits Subseries; or of the photograph described in Correspondence Series, Robert Hutchinson.
    - Wesleyan Methodist and Primitive Methodist conference groups, panoramic photographs, 19th and early 20th centuries, 7 items (Oversize-folder 6)
      Panoramic black-and-white photographs of Methodist meeting and conference groups. The earliest image is an albumen print of a Primitive Methodist meeting in Manchester, England, 1870. Other subjects include a White House reception for the Methodist Protestant Conference, 1931, and two images from meetings of the Methodist Unification Conference in Kansas City, Missouri, 1939.
- Printed Materials Series, 1536-1992 and undated, 4 boxes
  Broadsides, circular letters, newspapers, posters, announcements, original leaves and reproductions from historically significant editions of the Bible, and a wide variety of other ephemeral printed materials, arranged in the following three subseries: Broadsides and Circular Letters; Committee of Privileges; and Other Printed Materials. The first two subseries overlap in both format and subject, the main difference being that the Committee of Privileges materials were received as a discrete gift from FB, whereas the Broadsides and Circular Letters were gathered from numerous accessions of his papers. The Committee of Privileges material focuses mainly on the controversies in the decade after John Wesley's death in 1791. In addition to church conferences and controversies, another recurrent topic in these printed materials is the formation of a Missionary Society in the 1810s, which in turn opens up the topics of slavery, especially in the West Indies, and Methodist support of the abolitionist movement. Includes many single and fragmentary pieces of various printed materials, found at the end of the series.
  - Broadsides and Circular Letters Subseries, 1741, 1784-1891, and undated
    Broadsides, circular letters, posters, and other ephemeral printed materials. In particular, the items here extend into the 1840s and 1850s and touch upon some of the controversies of the Wesleyan Reform era. Material related to this subject can also be found in George Osborn's letter-book and album, "Collection of letters and broadsheets, &c., on Wesleyan Reform Movement," housed in the Volumes Series.
    - The Above [Kingston Wesleyan] Chapel Will Be Opened for Public Worship on Monday, June 14, 1841, [Hull], 1841 (Box PM 1, Folder 1)
    - Address of the United Methodist Association to the Societies at Large., Liverpool: Egerton Smith,circa 1827 (Box PM 1)
      References Dr. Warren and the Rules of 1795 and 1797.
    - Allin, T., To the Members and Friends of the Methodist New Connexion, Sheffield: Ridge, 1837 Mar. (Box PM 1)
      Regarding resolutions passed on the Connexional Union between the Methodist New Connexion and the Wesleyan Association.
    - Allin, T., To the Members and Friends of the Methodist New Connexion, 1837 June 5 (Box PM 1)